<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ming Li&#39;s Group</title>
    <link>https://stat-phys.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ming Li&#39;s Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://stat-phys.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://stat-phys.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stat-phys.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me I received B.S. degree from Anhui University in 2009. Then, I studied the statistical physics as applied to complex networks and complex systems at University of Science and Technology of China, and received Ph.D. degree in 2014. From 2014 to 2016, I was a Post-doctoral Fellower in the Department of Modern Physics at University of Science and Technology of China. In the first half of 2016, I worked at Department of Applied Physics, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University as a Post-doctoral Fellower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://stat-phys.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stat-phys.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>If you have any questions, please feel free to contact me.
Affilication Department of Physics, Hefei University of Technology, Hefei, Anhui 230009, P. R. China
Email Email: lim@hfut.edu.cn
Social Google Scholar
ResearchGate</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>https://stat-phys.github.io/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stat-phys.github.io/members/</guid>
      <description>PI Prof. Ming Li Graduate Students Name Join Date Email Honor Qi Wang 2025 Xuewei Zhao 2023 Undergraduate Students Name Join Date Email Honor Chenglei Chen 2024 Guanyao Chen 2024 Yuanzhe Jiang 2024 Alumni Name Time in Group Degree Awarded Post-Graduation Destination Liwenying Yang (2024 National Scholarship) 2022-2025 Master of Physics New Oriental Zhenyu Yang (jointly with Dr. Hui Wang) 2021-2024 Master of Engineering China Telecom </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://stat-phys.github.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stat-phys.github.io/news/</guid>
      <description>News 2025-10-20 Congratulations to Xuewei Zhao on winning the 2025 National Scholarship for Graduate Students!
2025-09-15 Welcome Qi Wang to join our Lab as a master student.
2025-08-26 ​​Congratulations to Xuewei Zhao on the online publication of her first paper regarding percolation on scale-free networks!​​ Please see Chaos Soliton &amp;amp; Fractals for details.
2025-04-05 Our new paper on epidemic dynamics just hit the presses at Physical Review E.
2025-03-28 Our first paper of 2025 is out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://stat-phys.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stat-phys.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Since 2011, I have published 55 papers in collaboration with others in peer-reviewed journals. These publications include: Physics Reports (1), Physical Review Letters (1), National Science Review (1), Physical Review Research (2), Physical Review E (5), New Journal of Physics (2), Journal of Statistical Mechanics (4), Chaos (1), Chaos, Solitons &amp;amp; Fractals (3), Europhysics Letters (3), Physics Letters A (1), PLoS ONE (1), Scientific Reports (3), Physica A (8), Chinese Physics Letters (1), Chinese Physics B (5), Advances in Complex Systems (1), International Journal of Modern Physics C (2), Computer Networks (1), IEEE Transactions (1), conference proceedings (4), and journals in Chinese (4).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://stat-phys.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stat-phys.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Statistical Physics and Complex Systems My research lies at the intersection of statistical physics and complex systems, where I investigate the emergent behavior of interacting systems through the lens of phase transitions and critical phenomena. By leveraging analytical and computational tools, I aim to uncover universal principles governing the collective dynamics of systems ranging from simple lattice models to intricate real-world networks.
Phase Transitions and Critical Phenomena Phase transitions, where a system undergoes a qualitative change in its macroscopic properties, are a central theme in statistical physics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://stat-phys.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stat-phys.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>2025春季(Spring term 2025) 本科生课程(for undergraduate students): 热力学与统计物理 (Thermodynamics and Statistical Physics) 2024秋季(Autumn term 2024) 本科生课程(for undergraduate students): 新生研讨课 (Freshman Seminar)
做了一次报告(Contribute a lecture)
研究生课程(for graduate students): 学科前沿专题 (Lectures on Frontiers of the Discipline)
做了一次报告(Contribute a lecture)
2024春季(Spring term 2024) 研究生课程(for graduate students): 学科前沿专题 (Lectures on Frontiers of the Discipline)
做了一次报告(Contribute a lecture)
2023秋季(Autumn term 2023) 本科生课程(for undergraduate students): 新生研讨课 (Freshman Seminar)
做了一次报告(Contribute a lecture)
研究生课程(for graduate students): 高等统计物理 (Advanced Statistical Physics)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>中文</title>
      <link>https://stat-phys.github.io/chinese/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stat-phys.github.io/chinese/</guid>
      <description>基本情况 李明，博士，研究员/黄山学者特聘教授，合肥工业大学物理学院物理系。
研究领域（理论研究）: 统计物理与复杂系统。近期主要研究兴趣: 临界行为的动态分析方法、高维逾渗相变、随机游走、沙堆模型等。主要研究成果请见Publications或者谷歌学术。
招生情况 如果你在统计物理、计算物理、编程模拟、数学等一方面或多方面有所擅长，希望利用这些知识做些有趣的研究，或在科研中深入学习相关知识，欢迎加入我们（研究生、本科生均可）。交流沟通请发邮件至：lim@hfut.edu.cn。</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
